Guide to the Visual AIDS Records MSS.503
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series V. The Archive Project, 1986-2013; 6.50 Linear Feet in 11 manuscript boxes and 2 oversize flat boxes
  - Subseries V.B. Exhibits, 1995-2005; 2.70 Linear Feet in 4 manuscript boxes and 2 oversize flat boxes
    This subseries contains material related to exhibitions inspired by artists with files within the Archive Project. These exhibitions highlight the value Visual AIDS places on preserving and sharing the documentary artistic record of HIV-positive artists for the purposes of awareness, advocacy, and teaching. Notable exhibitions documented in this series include Visual AIDS / Works from the Archive Project; The First 10: The Archive Project; and Lightbox: An Exhibition of the Visual AIDS Archive Project. Materials typically found in these files include promotional materials, brochures, press clippings, press releases, images of artwork, and catalogs with related work files. A significant portion of this series focuses on the 1993 exhibition shown in Boston, Arts' Communities / AIDS' Communities: Realizing the Archive Project. These files include promotional materials, press clippings, correspondence, posters, catalog drafts and final copies, installation notes, photographs, and information related to the Hunter Reynolds Memorial Dress Performance. Also of note are paper and digital files related to the "Salon: A Selection of Work by Artists from the Archive Project" event including invitations, notes, and images from the event.
    - Visual AIDS / Works from the Archive Project -- Information Sheet, 1995 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - The First 10: The Archive Project -- Booklet, March 30 - April 23, 1995 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - God's Love We Deliver -- Art Release Forms for Exhibit, 1995 (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Arts' Communities / AIDS' Communities: Realizing the Archive Project -- Promotional Material, Press Clippings, Poster, February 20 - March 3, 1996 (Box 53, Folder 7-10, Box 65, Folder 14, Box 69, Folder 8)
    - Arts' Communities / AIDS' Communities: Realizing the Archive Project -- Hunter Reynolds Memorial Dress Performance Material, February 20 - March 3, 1996 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Arts' Communities / AIDS' Communities: Realizing the Archive Project -- Visitor Count Sheets, Loan Forms, Installation Notes and Photographs, February 20 - March 3, 1996 (Box 53, Folder 12-17)
    - Arts' Communities / AIDS' Communities: Realizing the Archive Project -- Catalogue Draft and Published Booklet, February 20 - March 3, 1996 (Box 54, Folder 1-2)
    - Co-Curated Exhibit, A Living Testament of the Blood Fairies -- Promotional Material, Letters, Press Clippings, Poster, January - March 1997 (Box 53, Folder 4, Box 65, Folder 15)
    - Salon: A Selection of Work by Artists From the Archive Project Event -- Invitations, Notes, Slide Photographs, February 23, 1998 (Box 54, Folder 3-4)
    - Lightbox: An Exhibition of the Visual AIDS Archive Project -- Brochures, Announcements, Artwork Images, Press Clippings, 2000-2005 (Box 54, Folder 5-9, Box 55, Folder 1-4)
    - Sight of Construction -- Announcements, Press Releases, Artwork and Installation Slide Images, May 31, 2001 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Subseries V.C. Artists' Files, 1986-2007; 3.70 Linear Feet in 7 manuscript boxes and 1 file within a shared flat box
    This series consists of material on the lives and work of artists with HIV/AIDS that were accumulated by the Archive Project to document those not adequately represented in the artistic community as a result of their death and the societal stigma surrounding HIV/AIDS in the late 1980s and 1990s. Artists' files typically contain statements, resumes, press clippings, and artwork images, as well as exhibition catalogs and promotional material.
    Due to the sensitive nature of HIV/AIDS disclosure, individual artists' names are not listed in this inventory.
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Artists' Last Name -- A, 1987-2002 (Box 55, Folder 8-16)
    - Artists' Last Name -- B, 1988-1998 (Box 55, Folder 17-22, Box 56, Folder 1-10)
    - Artists' Last Name -- C, 1988-2000 (Box 56, Folder 11-20)
    - Artists' Last Name -- D, 1988-2003 (Box 56, Folder 21-25, Box 57, Folder 1-3)
    - Artists' Last Name -- E, 1989-1996 (Box 57, Folder 4-8, Box Shared Fales 109, Folder 22)
    - Artists' Last Name -- F, 1989-1992 (Box 57, Folder 9-13)
    - Artists' Last Name -- G, 1987-2001 (Box 57, Folder 14-24)
    - Artists' Last Name -- H, 1989-2000 (Box 57, Folder 25-34)
    - Artists' Last Name -- J, 1989-1996 (Box 57, Folder 35, Box 58, Folder 1-2)
    - Artists' Last Name -- K, 1989-1993 (Box 58, Folder 3-6)
    - Artists' Last Name -- L, 1986-2001 (Box 58, Folder 7-17)
    - Artists' Last Name -- M, 1988-2007 (Box 58, Folder 18-34)
    - Artists' Last Name -- N, 1988-1990 (Box 58, Folder 35-38, Box 59, Folder 1-2)
    - Artists' Last Name -- O, 1989-1996 (Box 59, Folder 3-6)
    - Artists' Last Name -- P, 1988-1993 (Box 59, Folder 7-11)
    - Artists' Last Name -- Q, circa 1993 (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - Artists' Last Name -- R, 1986-2003 (Box 59, Folder 13-22)
    - Artists' Last Name -- S, 1988-2002 (Box 59, Folder 23-27, Box 60, Folder 1-17, Box Shared Fales 109, Folder 22)
    - Artists' Last Name -- T, 1988-2000 (Box 60, Folder 18, Box 61, Folder 1-9)
    - Artists' Last Name -- V, 1980s-1990s (Box 61, Folder 10-13)
    - Artists' Last Name -- W, 1987-1993 (Box 61, Folder 14-18)